原创翻译  双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
改编自《冰与火之歌》
原著 乔治·R·R·马丁
第六季 第四集
权力的游戏
你打算去哪里
Where you gonna go?
南边
South.
去干什么
What are you gonna do?
暖和暖和
Get warm.
艰难屯那一战我也在
I was with you at Hardhome.
我们看到外面有什么了
We saw what's out there.
我们都知道它会来
We know it's coming here.
你怎么能现在离开我们
How can you leave us now?
我已经尽了全力  你很清楚
I did everything I could. You know that.
-你发过誓  -对  我将生命献给守夜人
- You swore a vow. - Aye, I pledged my life to the Night's Watch.
-我已经献出了生命  -今夜如此  夜夜皆然
- I gave my life. - For all nights to come.
他们杀了我  艾迪  我的兄弟杀了我
They killed me, Edd! My own brothers.
出了这样的事你还要我留下
You want me to stay here after that?
骑兵靠近
Riders approaching!
开门
Open the gate!
原创翻译  双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻译：Silmar 草草 欧沈娜
■
翻译：盐湖凉开水 妖精希亚 泰斯
校对：泰斯·雪诺 Silmar   顾问：屈畅(ccxx)
时间轴：崽猪 加森 Avis
后期：吉吉·波顿  总监：泰斯·雪诺
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    美剧炸了
了解最新影视资讯字幕信息
汤不错
This is good soup.
还记得老奶妈做的腰子派吗
Do you remember those kidney pies Old Nan used to make?
配豌豆和洋葱的
With the peas and onions?
我们当初就不该离开临冬城
We never should have left Winterfell.
你不希望能回到我们离开那天吗
Don't you wish we could go back to the day we left?
我想对自己尖叫"不要走  你这白痴"
I want to scream at myself, "Don't go, you idiot."
我们当时怎会知道呢
How could we know?
我经常在想  我当初对你多糟糕
I spent a lot of time thinking about what an ass I was to you.
真希望能改变一切
I wish I could change everything.
那时候我们还小
We were children.
我对你糟透了  承认吧
I was awful, just admit it.
你有时候是有点糟
You were occasionally awful.
我确定我也不是什么开心果
I'm sure I can't have been great fun.
总在你们玩的时候蹲角落生闷气
Always sulking in the corner while the rest of you played.
-可以原谅我吗  -没什么需要原谅的
- Can you forgive me? - There's nothing to forgive.
-原谅我  -好吧
- Forgive me. - All right.
好吧  我原谅你
All right, I forgive you.
还以为守夜人千年传统
You'd think after thousands of years,
总该学会怎样酿出好麦酒了
the Night's Watch would have learned how to make a good ale.
你打算去哪里
Where will you go?
我们要去哪里
Where will we go?
我要是不照顾好你
If I don't watch over you,
父亲的鬼魂也要回来杀了我
Father's ghost will come back and murder me.
我们去哪儿
Where will we go?
我不能留在这里  发生了那种事
I can't stay here, not after what happened.
我们只有一个地方可去
There's only one place we can go.
回家
Home.
请老小波顿卷铺盖走人吗
Should we tell the Boltons to pack up and leave?
我们把家园夺回来
We'll take it back from them.
我没有军队
I don't have an army.
你救了多少野人
How many wildlings did you save?
他们不是来为我卖命的
They didn't come here to serve me.
他们的命是欠你的
They owe you their lives.
你以为卢斯·波顿继续做北境守护
You think they'll be safe here
他们留在这里能安全吗
if Roose Bolton remains Warden of the North?
-珊莎  -临冬城是我们的家
- Sansa. - Winterfell is our home.
我们的家  艾丽娅  布兰和瑞肯的家
It's ours and Arya's and Bran's and Rickon's.
不管他们身在何处  临冬城属于我们家族
Wherever they are, it belongs to our family.
我们必须为它而战
We have to fight for it.
我厌倦了战斗
I'm tired of fighting.
自从离家之后  我一直在战斗
It's all I've done since I left home.
我杀过守夜人的兄弟
I've killed brothers of the Night's Watch.
杀过野人  杀过我敬佩的人
I've killed wildlings. I've killed men that I admire.
我吊死了一个男孩  他比布兰还小
I hanged a boy younger than Bran.
我战斗过  我输了
I fought and I lost.
我们不夺回北境  永远都不能安全
If we don't take back the North, we'll never be safe.
我想要你帮助我
I want you to help me.
但如果别无选择  我一个人也要去
But I'll do it myself if I have to.
女士
My lady.
戴佛斯爵士
Ser Davos.
你会留在黑城堡吗
Will you stay here at Castle Black?
我听琼恩·雪诺吩咐
I will do as Jon Snow commands.
你现在为琼恩·雪诺服务了
You serve Jon Snow now?
他是预言中的王子
He's the prince that was promised.
抱歉  女士  我以为史坦尼斯才是
Forgive me, my lady, I thought that was Stannis.
南边发生了什么
What happened down there?
发生交战  史坦尼斯战败了
There was a battle. Stannis was defeated.
席琳呢
And Shireen?
公主怎么样了
What happened to the princess?
我看到了
I saw what happened.
我看到史坦尼斯的军队在战场上溃败
I saw Stannis' forces defeated in the field.
小姐  我是戴佛斯·席渥斯爵士
My lady, I'm Ser Davos Seaworth.
我们见过面
We've met before.
那时我是蓝礼的彩虹护卫
I was Kingsguard to Renly Baratheon.
在蓝礼被血魔法刺杀之前
Before Renly was assassinated with bloodmagic.
那是过去的事了
That's in the past now.
没错  是过去了
Yes, it's in the past.
但并不意味着我已经忘记
It doesn't mean I forget.
或者原谅
Or forgive.
他承认了  知道吗
He admitted it, you know.
谁承认了
Who did?
史坦尼斯
Stannis.
在我将他斩首之前
Just before I executed him.
谷地的守护者
The Defender of the Vale!
培提尔叔叔
Uncle Petyr!
大人
My lord.
过来看
Come and see.
我错过了你的命名日  快看吧
I missed your name day. Go on.
是隼
A falcon!
一只白隼
A gyrfalcon.
最勇猛稀有的鸟儿
The greatest and rarest of birds.
贝里席  我上次见到你时
Last time I saw you, Baelish,
你说你要带珊莎·史塔克回五指半岛
you told me you were taking Sansa Stark home with you to the Fingers.
的确如此
Indeed I was.
然而不久之前  我们收到消息
And yet not long ago, we received reports
她在临冬城跟拉姆斯·波顿成婚了
that she has been married to Ramsay Bolton in Winterfell.
我们在去五指半岛的路上
On our way to the Fingers,
遭遇了大批波顿家的人马
we were set upon by a large force of Bolton men.
他们好像非常清楚我们行程的时间
Seemed to know exactly when we were traveling
知道我们带着什么人
and exactly whom we were transporting.
你当我是傻瓜吗
Do you take me for a fool?
告诉我  罗伊斯大人
Tell me, Lord Royce,
有多少人知道我带珊莎·史塔克北上的计划
how many people knew of my travel plans with Sansa Stark?
我只对你透露过意图
I shared my intentions with you
再无第三人
and no one else.
在别人家里含血喷人
Slander a man in his own home,
容易被人刀剑相向
you might find yourself crossing swords with him.
你的家是谷地  谷地主君在此
Your home is the Vale. The Lord of the Vale stands before us.
我只关注他的意见
And only his judgment concerns me.
要把他从月门扔出去吗
Shall we throw him through the Moon Door?
大人
My lord.
大人  我一直对艾林家族忠心耿耿
My lord, I have always been faithful to House Arryn.
忠于您父亲  母亲  现在忠于您
To your father, to your mother, and now to you.
你信他吗  培提尔叔叔
Do you believe him, Uncle Petyr?
罗伊斯大人为谷地鞍前马后
Lord Royce has served the Vale well.
有过辉煌的军事生涯
He's enjoyed a distinguished military career.
若是我们能相信他绝对忠诚
If we could trust his absolute loyalty,
他可以在未来的战争中做一名称职的指挥官
he would make a capable commander in the wars to come.
您可以相信我绝对忠诚  大人
You can trust my absolute loyalty, my lord.
我想可以再给他一次机会  您说呢
I think he deserves one more chance. What do you say?
成
Fine.
我带来了好消息
I bring good news.
我北境的朋友告诉我珊莎逃离了临冬城
My friends in the North tell me Sansa has escaped Winterfell.
我猜她是去黑城堡了
I expect she's headed to Castle Black
她哥哥在那里做总司令
where her brother serves as Lord Commander.
但她在那儿并不安全  波顿家族在找她
But she won't be safe there, not with the Boltons after her.
她是我的表姐
She's my cousin.
我们该帮她
We should help her.
我也是这么想的
That was my instinct as well.
主君已经开口了
Our lord has spoken.
集结谷地骑士
Gather the Knights of the Vale.
参战的时候到了
The time has come to join the fray.
你把敌人请到我们城里来
You invite the enemy into our city?
是的
I did.
有一位智者曾对我说
As a clever man once told me,
"我们与敌人求和  而非朋友"
"We make peace with our enemies, not our friends."
我不跟女王的敌人求和
I don't make peace with the queen's enemies.
我杀女王的敌人
I kill the queen's enemies.
没错  那是军事手段
Yes, that's the military approach.
在弥林进展得如何呢
And how has that worked here in Meereen?
我采取外交手段
I represent the diplomatic approach.
女王试过跟奴隶主求和
Our queen tried to make peace with the Masters
他们却想谋害她
and they tried to murder her.
我们现在是清醒地与人谈判
We enter these negotiations with open eyes.
相信我  我前段时间的奴隶经历
Trust me. My own recent experience with slavery
让我体会了那种制度的可怕
has taught me the horrors of that institution.
你做了多久的奴隶
How many days were you a slave?
足够我体会了
Long enough to know.
还不足以真正理解
Not long enough to understand.
我用一枚金币买下了这个侏儒
I bought this dwarf for a single gold honor.
可不知怎么  你登上了
And somehow you've risen
弥林大金字塔的顶端
to the top of the Great Pyramid of Meereen.
真是厉害
It's most impressive.
现在你代表阿斯塔波的善主
And now you speak for the Good Masters of Astapor.
敬命运的无常
Here's to reversals of fortune.
我们是来见女王的
We came here to meet the queen
却是一个侏儒和一个太监来接待我们
and instead we're greeted by a dwarf and a eunuch.
我们简单说吧
Let's make this simple, shall we?
告诉我你们想要什么
Tell me what you want.
我们要你们离开奴隶湾
We want you to leave Slaver's Bay.
带上你们的龙和雇佣军走人
Take your dragons and your mercenaries and go.
丹妮莉丝女王没打算永远留在弥林
Queen Daenerys won't stay in Meereen forever.
她的路是通向西方的
Her path takes her westward.
我们上次见面时  我提出给她船
When we last met, I offered her ships
让她回维斯特洛  那才是她该去的地方
so she could return to Westeros where she belongs.
她拒绝了
She refused them.
她拒绝是因为成千上万的男人
She refused them because hundreds of thousands of men,
女人和孩子仍受奴役
women, and children still lived in chains.
一直以来都是这样
As they have since the dawn of time.
今后不会了
Not anymore.
你觉得你现在是自由民了吗
You think you're a free man now?
你不还是奉命行事
You still follow orders.
就因为你的主人有银发和奶子
Just because your master has silver hair and tits
并不代表她不是主人
doesn't mean she's not a master.
朋友们  朋友们  拜托
Friends, friends, friends, please.
总是一部分人
There have always been those
有钱有权  一部分人没有
with wealth and power and those with nothing.
世道如此
That is the way of the world.
我不是来改变世道的
I'm not here to change the way of the world.
奴隶制是我们的世道
Slavery is the way of our world.
你不需要奴隶也能挣钱
You don't need slaves to make money.
维斯特洛已经几百年没奴隶了
There haven't been slaves in Westeros for hundreds of years
我的家族可比你们都富有多了
and I grew up richer than any of you.
但我们的女王明白她错在
But our queen recognizes that she erred by
废除了奴隶制
abolishing slavery
却不能提供一个新的替代制度
without providing a new system to replace it.
所以  女王提出了这个建议
So here is the queen's proposal.
弥林绝不会再恢复奴隶制
Slavery will never return to Meereen,
但她愿给奴隶湾其他的城市
but she will give the other cities of Slaver's Bay
适应新秩序的时间
time to adjust to the new order.
那是什么意思
What does that mean?
我们不会一夜之间废除奴隶制
Instead of abolishing slavery overnight,
而是给你们七年时间结束它
we will give you seven years to end the practice.
奴隶主的损失会得到赔偿
Slaveholders will be compensated for their losses,
而且价格合理
of course, at fair prices.
作为交换  你们停止
In exchange, you will cut off
对鹰身女妖之子的资助
your support for the Sons of the Harpy.
我们没有资助鹰身女妖之子
We do not support the Sons of the Harpy.
好吧  反正你们停止就是了
Fine, fine, but you will cut it off all the same.
希望你们接受  朋友们
I do hope you accept, my friends.
你们不会得到更好的提议了
You will not receive a better offer.
我们要乘着自由之浪扬帆
Let us sail on the tide of freedom
而不是被它淹没
instead of being drowned by it.
这是送给贵宾的离别礼物
And as a parting gift to our honored guests...
给自由一个机会
Give freedom a chance.
看看是不是和之前的滋味一样好
See if it doesn't taste every bit as good as what came before.
朋友们
灰常抱歉
让你们等了那么多时间
还是让我替你翻译吧
Perhaps I should translate for you.
我们会说通用语
We speak the Common Tongue.
-太好了  -你今天见了奴隶主
- Excellent. - You met with the slavers today.
是的
I did.
我们的兄弟姐妹为抗击这帮混账而死
Our brothers and sisters died fighting this scum.
现在你把他们请到城里来  跟他们喝酒
Now you invite them to our city and drink wine with them.
我猜建造这座宫殿是为了
I imagine this room was built
让统治者震慑其子民的
so the rulers could intimidate the ruled.
但我不是你们的统治者
But I am not your ruler.
我不是解放者
I'm not the Breaker of Chains.
我不是不焚者
I'm not the Unburnt.
我更不是龙之母
And I am certainly not the Mother of Dragons.
你是个异乡人
You are a stranger here.
你凭什么代表弥林跟敌人谈判
So why do you represent Meereen in these talks with our enemies?
因为女王选了我做顾问
Because our queen chose me as her advisor.
直到她结束行程归来
Until she returns from her travels...
她什么时候回来
When does she return?
快了  我保证
Soon. You have my word.
我们不认识你  不信任你  我们认识灰虫子
We don't know you. We don't trust you. We know Torgo Nudho.
我们跟他一起抗击伟主  我们信任他
We fight with him against the Masters. We trust him.
所以灰虫子也参与了谈判
And that is exactly why grey Worm took part in these negotiations.
作为无垢者的指挥官  他知道如何打败奴隶主
As commander of the Unsullied, he knows how to defeat the slavers
他也知道何时该讲和
and he knows when it is time to make peace.
你跟奴隶主讲和了
You have made peace with the slavers?
我们提出了条件
We offered terms.
你呢  灰虫子
你想跟他们一起喝酒吗
那些把我们从母亲手里夺走  把我们当牲畜卖掉的人
我是战士  不是政治家
但如果有机会获得和平
公正的和平
我们该接受
弥桑黛
你知道他们是谁  你怎么能信任他们
我不信任他们  我永远不会信任他们
但有一位智者曾说
"我们与敌人求和  而非朋友"
-别利用我撒谎  -他们尊敬你
- Do not use me for your lies. - Those men respect you.
他们尊敬我是因为了解我
They respect me because they know who I am.
-他们知道我忠诚  -我也是
- They know I am loyal. - As do I.
我忠于女王  不是你
I am loyal to my queen, not you.
如果你背叛她的事业  你就是我的敌人
If you betray her work, you are my enemy.
我没有背叛她的事业  我在拯救她的城市
I am not betraying her work. I am trying to save her city.
你答应让奴隶主保留奴隶制
You promised the slavers they could keep slavery.
暂时而已
For a short time.
七年对奴隶来说可不是"暂时"
Seven years is not a short time for a slave.
你说得对
You're right.
奴隶制很残酷  应该马上终止
Slavery is a horror that should be ended at once.
战争也很残酷  应该马上终止
War is a horror that should be ended at once.
但我今天都做不到
I can't do both today.
你不该信任那些人
You are wrong to trust these men.
我信任的不是奴隶主  而是他们的自身利益
I don't trust the Masters. I trust their self-interest.
如果他们相信与我合作
They're trustworthy if they're convinced
符合自身利益  他们就是可信的
that working with me is in their self-interest.
你不认识他们  你不了解他们
You don't know them. You don't understand them.
在他们眼中  我们根本不是人
We are not human in their eyes.
他们把我看作武器
They look at me and see a weapon.
他们把她看作妓女
They look at her and see a whore.
他们把我看作一个畸形的小怪物
They look at me and they see a misshapen little beast.
轻蔑是他们的弱点
Their contempt is their weakness.
他们每次低估我们
They'll underestimate us every time
都是我们可资利用的良机
and we will use that to our advantage.
你无法利用他们
You will not use them.
他们会利用你  他们就是这样做的
They will use you. That is what they do.
你还好吗
You all right?
不如坐下喘口气吧
Why don't you sit and catch your breath?
我好得很
I'm fine.
我觉得你驾驭不了龙
I don't think you could ride the dragon.
二十年前还有可能
20 years ago, maybe.
-什么  -我们的女王
- What? - Our queen.
她野得很  别被她的小身板迷惑了
She's wild, you know. Don't let her size fool you.
对我来说都不容易  何况我还年轻
It's hard enough for me and I'm a young man.
至于你  我觉得你的心脏承受不起
You, I don't think your heart could take it.
女王选了我  你肯定很生气
Must make you angry that our queen chose me.
我很伤心  过不了多久你就会让她失望
Makes me sad. You'll disappoint her before long.
她不会再找你
She'll move on.
过不了多久我们都会让她失望
We'll all disappoint her before long.
我们现在要互帮互助
We need each other right now.
等到这件事过去了
After we're done needing each other...
我不想跟你打  安达尔人乔拉
Oh, I don't want to fight you, Jorah the Andal.
对我有什么好处
What do I have to gain?
如果我赢了  我是杀掉老头的废柴
If I win, I'm the shit who killed an old man.
如果我输了  我是被老头杀掉的废柴
If I lose, I'm the shit who was killed by an old man.
你小时候没受过什么家教吧
You didn't get much discipline as a child, did you?
完全没有
None.
这条路通向马门
The road running through the Horse Gate,
他们称其为诸神大道
they call that the godsway.
这边是东市  那边是西市
Eastern Market, Western Market.
卓戈卡奥死时
When Khal Drogo died,
她理应回到这里  加入多希卡林
she was supposed to come here and join the Dosh Khaleen,
与卡奥的寡妻同住
the widows of the dead khals.
那应该就是她被带去的地方
That's where they would have taken her,
多希卡林的圣地
the Temple of the Dosh Khaleen.
你干什么
What are you doing?
不能带武器进入圣城
It's forbidden to carry weapons in the sacred city.
偷偷溜进去抢走卡丽熙
Isn't it forbidden to sneak
就可以了吗
into their city and steal their khaleesi?
如果他们发现我们  但没带武器
If they spot us and we're unarmed,
我们可以自称是前往西市的商人
we'll say we're traders heading for the Western Market.
但如果他们看到了武器...
But if they see weapons...
这不是让狗拔掉自己的牙齿吗
You're asking a dog to hand over his teeth.
里面有十万多斯拉克人
There's 100,000 of them down there.
我们可没法杀出去
We can't fight our way out.
我们等到天黑  然后进去找她
We wait till dark, and then we'll find her.
我特别喜欢这把刀
I'm very attached to this knife.
放心  没有碰到你
Don't worry. It didn't touch you.
你知道后果吗
You know what happens?
我知道
I know what happens.
我自己来
I'll do it myself.
如果我是多斯拉克人该多好
I should have been born a Dothraki.
走吧
Come on.
朋友
我们从西市溜达出来  结果迷路了
可以给我们指指路吗
你们是卖什么的
卖酒的
明天来我的货摊
送你们一桶青亭岛的佳酿
你不是商人
去找人来
告诉过你  我特别喜欢这把刀
Told you, I'm very attached to this knife.
你还好吗
You all right?
如果他们发现有人被刺死
If they find a body with a stab wound,
全城的人都会追捕我们
the whole city will be looking for us.
她们有些人觉得多斯拉克人不该与异族结婚生子
都是无知的老妪  她们不知道我们的血统一直在稀释
她是拉扎林人
卡奥烧了她的村子  发现她藏在井里
你那时多大
十二岁
一年后她为卡奥产下女儿  他的反应如何
他打断了我的肋骨
我们在这里不是王后  但卡奥有求于我们的智慧
我们活着是有意义的
那比大多数人都好
等卡奥明晚会集  但愿他们允许你与我们活到终老
其余的路可没那么舒坦
我去更衣
你逃不出多斯拉克
你知道的
我永远不会从多斯拉克逃跑
给她带路
我需要换换气
老女人身上臭死了
是很臭
你的卡奥去世时  你还很年轻吧
十六岁
可惜他没早点死
是啊  可惜了
你真的有三条龙吗
它们会喷火吗
会的
你以后想见见吗
我是多希卡林
我永远不能离开维斯·多斯拉克  直到死后化为青烟
-不  别伤害她  -她会出卖我们的
- No, don't hurt her. - She'll give us away.
我们得走了
We have to go now.
最新美剧下载
www.ZiMuZu.tv
我们不可能活着走出维斯·多斯拉克
We will never get out of Vaes Dothrak alive.
我们只能试试了
All we can do is try.
不
No.
我们可以换个办法
We can do more than that.
你们要帮我
And you're going to help me.
至于你
要相信我  卡丽熙
不要背叛我
如果我现在让你离开  你打算去哪儿
If I were to let you leave right now, where would you go?
你会寻求什么
What would you seek out?
我会找我的哥哥
I'd go to my brother,
找我的丈夫  还有家人
my husband, my family.
当然了  但是那对你来说意味着追寻财富
Of course, but for you, that means seeking out money,
锦衣玉食和权力
finery, power.
追寻你的家人就是追寻罪恶
Seeking out your family means seeking out sin.
我不是在贬低你
I'm not maligning you.
我也曾追寻过那些东西
I sought those things out, too.
别的什么也顾不上
To the exclusion of all else.
我父亲是个鞋匠
My father was a cobbler.
在我小的时候就去世了  我继承了他的店铺
He died when I was young and I took over his shop.
他是个简单的人  造的是简单的鞋子
He was a simple man and he made simple shoes.
但是我发现我在鞋子上投入精力越多
But I found that the more work I put into my shoes,
人们就越想购买它们
the more people wanted them.
精致的皮革  装饰和点缀
Fine leather, ornamentation,
细节  还有时间
detailing, and time.
尤其是时间
Time most of all.
每双鞋都倾注了我数十小时的心血
Dozens of hours spent on a single pair.
好东西需要时间打磨
Quality takes time.
没错
Yes.
我觉得你应该穿过
I imagine you've worn a year
某些人用一整年生命织作的衣服
of someone's life on your back.
贵族们喜欢把我的心血穿在脚上
The highborn liked to cover their feet with my time
并愿意为此付出丰厚的报酬
and they paid well for the privilege.
我用那些钱
I used their money
也享受了一把他们那种生活
to buy a taste of their lives for myself.
每次放纵的时候
Each time I indulged,
我都感觉自己的层次提升了
I felt myself ascending to something better.
然后有一天你走过墓地
And one day you walked through a graveyard
意识到一切都是徒劳
and realized it was all for nothing
并迈步踏上正途
and set out on the path to righteousness.
《陌客之书》第二十五节
Book of the Stranger, verse 25.
你知道《七星圣经》
You know "The Seven-Pointed Star."
乌尼亚修女给我读过  冲我读过
Septa Unella reads it to me. At me.
是啊  她就喜欢冲着人念经
Yes, yes, she does enjoy reading at people.
你猜得差不离
You're close.
但不是在墓地
But it wasn't a graveyard.
而是在一次宴会上
It was a feast.
我准备了陈年美酒
I bought old fine wine
和妙龄美女
and young pretty girls
邀请我的朋友们来共享
and invited my friends to come and share it all.
我们享用着美酒和美女
We passed around the wine, passed around the women,
很快就不省人事了
and soon we fell into a stupor.
我快到天亮才醒过来
I woke before dawn.
连站都站不稳
I could barely stand.
其他人还在长椅或者地上沉睡
Everyone else was asleep on the couches or on the floor,
横七竖八地躺在他们华丽的衣服边
lying in heaps next to their fine clothes.
他们真实的肉体一览无余
The truth of their bodies laid bare.
我能闻到他们
I could smell them
掩在焚香和香水底下的气味
beneath the incense and the perfume
珍馐美馔也开始泛酸
and the fine food that had already started to turn.
我一清二楚地看到了
And I saw it with perfect clarity.
我看到了我的罪恶所在
I saw what my sins were.
我拥有的黄金  畅饮的美酒  玩弄的女人
The gold I had, the wine I drank, the women I used,
我为了保住地位而不遗余力的挣扎
my ceaseless struggle to maintain my position.
这些都是故事的一部分
It was all part of a story.
一个关于曾经的我的故事
A story I was telling myself about who I was.
一个个
A collection of lies
见光即死的谎言
that would disappear in the light.
那些我试图远离的人
The people I was trying to climb away from,
街上的乞丐
the beggars in the street,
穷人
the poor,
他们比曾经的我更真实
they were closer to the truth than I ever was.
所以你做了什么
So what did you do?
我出去寻找他们
I left to go and find them.
连鞋都没穿
I didn't even put on my shoes.
我走出大门  再也没有回来
I walked out the door and never went back.
来  我们去看他
Come, let's go and see him.
-看谁  -你哥哥
- Who? - Your brother.
洛拉斯
Loras.
听我说
Listen to me.
你一定要坚强
You need to stay strong.
我没法坚强
I can't stay strong.
我从来都没有坚强过
I never was strong.
你是坚强的
You are strong.
你是我们家族的未来
You are the future of our house,
全家的希望
the future of our family.
那些我都不在乎
I don't care about that.
你...你跟他们说过吗
Have you... have you told them that?
说过你不在乎吗
That you don't care?
我只想这一切都结束
I just want it to stop.
帮帮我
Help me.
他们想让我来帮你
They want me to help you.
他们想利用我打垮你
They want me to help tear you down.
这就是他允许我见你的原因  我知道了
That's why he's letting me see you. I know it is.
只要我们其中一个向他们屈服  他们就赢了
And if either of us give in to what they want, then they win.
那就让他们赢吧
Let them win.
让一切都结束吧
Just make it stop.
求你了
Please.
好了
All right.
鉴于我们目前的困境  该怎样避免灾难
And now, how to avert disaster with our current predicament.
那个大麻雀
This High Sparrow.
我和各种各样的狂热分子都打过交道  陛下
I have dealt with fanatics of every description, Your Grace.
最重要的一点  就是别把他们惹急了
Not setting them off, that's the most important thing.
您现在是内外交困
You are beset with enemies both within and without.
你在这里做什么
What are you doing here?
我向国王陛下建议如何处理目前的局势
I am advising the king on our current predicament.
-走开  -我是御前会议的成员
- Leave. - I am a member of the small council.
国王陛下...
The king...
这是御前会议吗
Is this a small council meeting?
当然不是
Obviously not.
我来提供我的智慧和支持
I'm here to lend my wisdom and my support.
多谢你的建议  大学士
Thank you for your counsel, Grand Maester.
就到这里吧
That will be all for now.
遵命
Your Grace.
由于我缺席了前几次御前会议
Since I've missed the past several small council meetings,
我有些事情想跟你说
I wanted to speak to you about a few things.
我一直在想办法对付大麻雀
I've been thinking about the High Sparrow.
不幸的是  我们都在想办法
As have we all, unfortunately.
对付这样一个人  我们要格外小心
We need to be careful in dealing with such a man.
不能让事态再恶化
To prevent things from escalating any further.
我们得谨慎行事  不要激怒他
We have to be careful not to antagonize him.
他手上有玛格丽  我们不能让她处于险境
He has Margaery. We can't put her at risk.
-他很危险  -看着我
- He's dangerous. - Look at me.
他们对我做了什么
What did they do to me?
我可是国王的生母
To the king's own mother?
没关系
It's all right.
一切都过去了
It's done. It's in the past.
当然
And of course
玛格丽的安危至关重要
Margaery's safety is paramount.
您不喜欢玛格丽  对吗
You don't like Margaery, do you?
我是否喜欢她一点都不重要
Whether I like her or not is completely unimportant.
玛格丽是王后
Margaery is the queen.
王后必须得到尊重  国王更是如此
Queens must command respect. Kings even more so.
这不仅关系国王和王后  也关系到所有人
Not just for their own sake, but for everyone's.
大麻雀对国王与王后毫不尊重
The High Sparrow has no respect for kings or queens.
也不尊重世上的一切
No respect for anything in this world.
世间万物对他毫无用处
He has no use for the things of this world.
他想推翻一切  然后用什么来替代呢
He wants to knock them down and replace them with what?
用幻想
With fantasies.
用街上的乞丐
With beggars in the street.
用无足轻重的东西
With nothing.
母亲
Mother...
有件事我要告诉你
there's something I want to tell you.
是大麻雀告诉我的
Something the High Sparrow told me.
你跟他谈过了吗
You've spoken with him?
我向他保证过不告诉任何人
I promised him I wouldn't tell anyone.
如果他发现我告诉了...
If he found out I told...
那便是泄露机密
It would be a breach of confidence
不跟你讲一通大道理
which he would not take lightly
他是不会善罢甘休的
given his constant prattling about the truth.
我是你母亲
I am your mother.
你可以相信我
You can always trust me.
奉国王之令
The small council meeting
御前会议推迟举行
has been postponed on the king's orders.
我以为我们之前说得很清楚了
I would have thought we were perfectly clear the first time.
我们不欢迎你
You're not welcome.
你曾说过你尊敬我父亲
You once spoke of your respect for our father
因为他懂得与对手合作的必要性
because he understood the necessity of working with one's rivals.
亲爱的  你已被剥夺了尊严和权威
My dear, you have been stripped of your dignity and authority,
公开受辱  禁足红堡
publically shamed, and confined to the Red Keep.
还拿什么来合作
What's left to work with?
瑟曦是国王的母亲
Cersei is the mother of the king.
国王听从并信任她
She has the king's ear and his trust.
而且国王正在定期同大麻雀
And the king has been speaking regularly
谈论玛格丽王后和洛拉斯爵士的事情
with the High Sparrow about Queen Margaery and Ser Loras.
大麻雀深知他夺权之后
The High Sparrow seized power knowing full well
我们只会窝里斗  而不是发起反击
we'd bicker amongst ourselves instead of seizing it back.
就像这样  我们做得多好
Here we are. Well done to us.
现在七国的未来
Now the future of the Seven Kingdoms
都握在那个乡巴佬的脏手里
rests in his dirty peasant hands.
过几天  他要对我进行审判
In a few days, he'll have a trial for me.
而在此之前  玛格丽王后将踏上她的赎罪之旅
But before that, Queen Margaery will make her walk of atonement.
是的  玛格丽将在全城的善男信女面前
Yes, Margaery will repent her sins
忏悔她的罪行
before the good people of the city.
不
Oh, no.
不能这样
That cannot happen.
不会这样的
That will not happen.
我同意
I agree.
你拥有维斯特洛第二强大的军队
You've got the second largest army in Westeros.
何不召进城来
You'll bring them into the city,
阻止他们羞辱玛格丽王后
stop Queen Margaery's humiliation before it starts,
带她重回宫中
and take her back into Crown custody.
国王命令我
The king has ordered me
不要对大麻雀和战士之子采取行动
to take no action against the High Sparrow
以免威胁到王后的人身安全
or the Faith Militant out of fear for the queen's safety.
你完全不必采取行动
You will take no action at all.
当提利尔的军队进城时  你就按兵不动
When the Tyrell armies come, you will stand down.
你被明令禁止按兵不动吗
Are you expressly forbidden from standing down?
没有  但是如果国王下令...
No, but if the king should call...
在你听到任何人的
The whole thing will be over
任何命令之前  整件事情就结束了
before anyone can call on you to do anything.
当大麻雀被捕  或是更好的情况  死了
When the High Sparrow is in custody or dead, preferably,
而玛格丽回到了托曼身边时
and Margaery's back at Tommen's side,
你认为国王还会对结果不满吗
do you think the king will be angry at the outcome?
你跟我们一样憎恨这些宗教狂徒
You hate these fanatics as much as we do.
你憎恨他们对你儿子的所作所为
You hate what they've done to your son.
你想让蓝赛尔回来吗
Do you want Lancel back?
还是你已经彻底放弃他了
Or have you given him up for good?
我当然希望他回来
Of course I want him back.
那就不要插手
Then stand aside
让那些夺走他的人垮台
and let the people that took him from you be destroyed.
如果事情没有按计划进行
If it doesn't go as planned,
麻雀们在城中有很多朋友
the sparrows have many friends in this city.
到时候就是一场内战  会死很多人
We'll have civil war. Many will die.
不论我们做什么都会死很多人
Many will die no matter what we do.
他们死总比我们死强
Better them than us.
他们跟我说你回家了我还不信
They told me you were home and I didn't believe it.
"席恩·葛雷乔伊吗"  我问
"Theon Greyjoy?" I said.
"他死了
"He's dead.
他死很久了"
He's been dead a long time."
他把你放了吗
He let you go?
我逃出来了
I escaped.
我听不见
I can't hear you.
我逃出来了
I escaped.
看着我
Look at me.
Look at me!
好多人为了救你而死
Men died trying to rescue you.
得力干将
Good men.
我的手下
My men.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你是我弟弟
You were my brother.
你是个被惯坏的小贱人  但你仍然是我弟弟
You were a spoiled little cunt, but you were my brother
而我为你付出一切
and I risked everything for you
你却背叛了我
and you betrayed me.
我知道  我知道  我很抱歉
I know. I know and I'm sorry.
别说了
Stop saying that.
他打垮了我
He broke me.
他把我粉碎成一千块
He broke me into 1,000 pieces.
-我知道  -你不知道
- I know. - You don't know.
他给我们送来了一块
He sent us one of those pieces.
所以我才跑去救你
That's why I came for you.
你为什么来这儿
Why did you come here?
我还能去哪儿
Where else could I go?
你听说父亲死了  就想自己来称王吗
You heard Father was dead and you thought you'd claim the crown?
没有  靠岸后我才听到他的死讯
No, no. I only heard he died after we docked.
你在选王会之前碰巧出现在派克岛吗
You happen to show up on Pyke right before the kingsmoot?
我根本不知道
I didn't know.
你觉得就凭你那些劣迹
You think any ironborn wants you to be king
哪个铁种会认你当国王
after what you've done?
我不想当国王
I don't want to be king.
那你想干什么
What do you want?
我早该听你的  你是唯一...
I should have listened to you. You're the only one...
那些不重要  别哭了
That doesn't matter anymore. Stop crying.
看着我
Look at me.
告诉我你想干什么
Tell me what you want.
你来统治铁群岛
You should rule the Iron Islands.
让我来辅佐你
Let me help you.
他们把你洗干净啦
They've cleaned you up nicely.
你知道我是谁吗
You know who I am?
一个老爷
A lord.
是的
Yes.
一个老爷
A lord.
你看见我的旗帜了吗
You've seen my banners?
剥皮人
The flayed man.
吓到你了吗
Does that worry you at all?
你过后会吃掉他们吗
You eat them after?
不会
No.
那我还见过更吓人的
Then I've seen worse.
你效忠过史塔克家族吗
You served the Starks?
是啊  他们给我戴上镣铐
Aye. They put me in chains
用剑指着我的喉咙
and put a sword at my throat,
所以我效忠他们
so I served them.
史塔克家族已经消失很久了
The Starks have been gone for a long time,
但你还在保护瑞肯
but you kept protecting Rickon.
找到合适的买家后他能卖个好价钱
He'd fetch a good price to the right buyer.
我效忠了他们家很久
I served his family a long time.
一点工钱都没拿到
Didn't get no wages.
我觉得  他们欠我的
Way I see it, I'm owed.
无论如何
Be that as it may,
现在你也不能卖掉瑞肯了
Rickon's not yours to sell anymore.
他是我的了
He's mine.
那么我留着你有何用呢
So what use could I possibly have for you?
我可以满足你的需要
I can give you what you want.
你知道我需要什么吗
And you're sure you know what that is?
男人们想要的都一样
Same thing men always want.
他们真的想要时  就会先洗干净
And when they really want it, they give it a bath first.
你可真会说话
You're a good talker.
我喜欢
I like that.
你比席恩·葛雷乔伊会说多了
You're a much better talker than Theon Greyjoy.
是吗
That so?
为了让他说话  我费了不少工夫
I had to work hard to get him talking.
但他说了
But he talked.
换谁都会说
They all do.
他什么都告诉我了
He told me everything.
说到史塔克家的小子
All about the Stark boys,
是谁帮他们逃跑
who helped them escape,
以及她是怎么帮的
and how she did it.
开门
Open the gate!
招待不周
Sorry about the food.
我们不擅长烧火做饭
It's not what we're known for.
没关系  你们有更重要的事情要操心
That's all right. There are more important things.
您的信  总司令大人
A letter for you, Lord Commander.
我已经不是总司令了
I'm not Lord Commander anymore.
"致叛徒和野种琼恩·雪诺
"To the traitor and bastard Jon Snow.
你让成千上万的野人越过长城
You allowed thousands of wildlings past the Wall.
你背叛了你的同胞
You have betrayed your own kind.
你背叛了整个北境
You have betrayed the North.
临冬城是我的  野种  来瞧瞧吧
Winterfell is mine, bastard. Come and see.
你弟弟瑞肯在我地牢里
Your brother Rickon is in my dungeon.
他那头冰原狼的狼皮铺在我地板上
His direwolf's skin is on my floor.
来瞧瞧吧  我要我的新娘
Come and see. I want my bride back.
把她交出来  野种
Send her to me, bastard,
我就放过你和你心爱的野人们
and I will not trouble you or your wildling lovers.
敢不交出来  我就率军北上
Keep her from me and I will ride north and slaughter
杀光受你保护的所有野人  不分男女老幼
every wildling man, woman, and babe living under your protection.
你会看着我将他们活活剥皮  你..."
You will watch as I skin them living. You... "
继续
Go on.
接下来的都差不多
It's just more of the same.
"你会看着我的手下轮奸你妹妹
"You will watch as my soldiers take turns raping your sister.
你会看着我的猎犬
You will watch as my dogs
啃食你的小弟弟
devour your wild little brother.
然后我剜出你的眼珠子
Then I will spoon your eyes
剩下的活儿交给猎犬
from their sockets and let my dogs do the rest.
来瞧瞧吧  拉姆斯·波顿  临冬城伯爵
Come and see. Ramsay Bolton, Lord of Winterfell
北境守护"
and Warden of the North."
临冬城伯爵  北境守护
Lord of Winterfell and Warden of the North.
他父亲死了
His father's dead.
拉姆斯杀的
Ramsay killed him.
-现在他抓了瑞肯  -我们不清楚
- And now he has Rickon. - We don't know that.
肯定就是
Yes, we do.
他的军队有多少人
How many men does he have in his army?
我听他说过五千
I heard him say 5,000 once
那是准备反击史坦尼斯的时候
when he was talking about Stannis's attack.
你有多少人
How many do you have?
能行军打仗的
That can march and fight?
两千
2,000.
剩下的全是孩子和老人
The rest are children and old people.
你是最后一任真正的北境守护的儿子
You're the son of the last true Warden of the North.
北方的家族忠心耿耿
Northern families are loyal.
只要你开口他们就为你而战
They'll fight for you if you ask.
那个怪物占了我们的家  抓了我们的弟弟
A monster has taken our home and our brother.
我们必须回临冬城  守护家园和亲人
We have to go back to Winterfell and save them both.
圣城不可见血
圣城不许带武器
那我们就不见血
不过呢  总要流点血的
有人用石头砸烂了他的脑袋
阿戈属于我的卡拉萨
他的活儿干得不错
他的脑袋被石头砸烂了
去他的阿戈
带卓戈的遗孀进来
这么个小人儿  管她作甚
我喜欢她
她比牛奶还白
我想尝尝卡丽熙的滋味
好啊
你可以舔我的老二
她属于多希卡林
渊凯的贤主想要她
他们愿意拿一万匹马交换
哪个值钱
一个粉红小丫头还是一万匹马
操那帮贤主的香薰屁股
老子亲自找他们要马
你们不想知道我的想法吗
你愿意被卖作奴隶吗
还是愿意让拉戈尝尝你的滋味
不
我都不想
我们不在乎你的想法
这里是多希卡林的圣地
你别无选择
除非你是多希卡林
但你现在还不是  要由我们决定
我知道这里  我以前来过
多希卡林在这里宣布我的孩子是骑着世界的骏马
然后呢
你傻乎乎地相信一个巫魔女的话
你的孩子因你而死
卓戈卡奥也是
卓戈在这里承诺  要带着卡拉萨西行到世界尽头
骑着木马横渡黑色咸水  做出古往今来其他卡奥从未做过的事
他说要杀死穿铁衣服的人  拆了他们的石头房子
他在圣母山前向我发誓
而你竟然傻到相信他
可是现在  伟大的卡奥们在这里谈论什么大事呢
要洗劫哪些小村庄
要玩弄多少姑娘  要敌人献上多少匹马
你们胸无大志
没有一个适合领导多斯拉克
但我适合
我也将会领导
行了
多希卡林不要你
我们会轮流操你
然后让我们的血盟卫操你
如果到时候你还剩点皮肉
我们就让马来操
你这个疯婊子
你真以为我们会为你效力
你们不会为我效力
你们会死
█
一大波正版授权“权力的游戏”周边向你靠近！
手机淘宝扫描左侧二维码
一起加入剧粉队伍～
搜索微信公众号
宅电社动漫 有福利哦
█
特别鸣谢人人影视